Guide to the Rice University Dean of Continuing Education records, 1987-2001 UA 229
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Dean of Continuing Education records
1987-2001
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University. Continuing Studies Program.
UA 229
0.5 Linear Feet (1 Box)
The Dean of Continuing Education Records contain materials related to the Dean of Continuing Education, specifically Mary McIntire. These records consist of financial statements, blueprints, images, proposals, correspondence, student publications, pamphlets, and surveys. The records begin in 1987 and continue through 2001, with the bulk of the information starting in the early 1990s.
Biographical/Historical Note
Founded in 1968, the Susanne M. Glasscock School of Continuing Studies now enrolls more than 12,000 people into programs in professional development, personal development, and languages. The school promotes personal and professional development for the larger Houston community, offering daytime and evening courses. The professional development program includes courses on career development, communication skills, financial education, and human resource education. The personal development program includes courses in the arts, humanities, sciences, photography, and creative writing. The School of Continuing Studies also offers a program to allow working adults to obtain their Master of Liberal Studies degree.
Mary McIntire became the founding Dean of Continuing Education in 1986 after a strong career in the School of Continuing Studies for over ten years. Mary McIntire continued to support Rice University throughout her career not only as Dean of Continuing Education, but as chair of various committees including the KTRU and Audio/Visual Committee. Dr. McIntire has recieved awards for supporting women in education and was named Houston Women's Federation Woman of the Year in 1997. See gscs.rice.edu for more information.
Scope and Contents
The Dean of Continuing Education Records contain materials related to the Dean of Continuing Education, specifically Mary McIntire. These records consist of financial statements, blueprints, images, proposals, correspondence, student publications, pamphlets, and surveys. The records begin in 1987 and continue through 2001, with the bulk of the information starting in the early 1990s.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at woodson@rice.edu for assistance in accessing these files.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Arrangement
These records are arranged in two series: Mary McIntire: Committees and Projects and Oversize Materials.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Women
Document Types
notes; architectural drawings (visual works); letters (correspondence)
Subjects (Persons)
McIntire, Mary
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Continuing Studies Program.
- Series I: Mary McIntire: Committees and Projects, 149825
  - Baker Institute for Public Policy groundbreaking, 1992-1994; 149826 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Centennial Committee, 1987-1989; 149827 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rice University Radio Station (KTRU), 1997-2000; 149828 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Radio Station, 1996-1997; 149829 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS), 1994-1996; 149830 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AV Committee, 1990-1991; 149831 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Berlin Wall, 1991-2001; 149832 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Oversize Materials, 160670
  - Architectural drawings of Media Center Courtyard and Continuing Studies Courtyard, 1991; 160671 (Map-drawer 148, Item 1)
    General Note
    Rice University Architectural drawings, oversize manuscript material, maps and photographs, Part 3 of 3 (UA 226-3) http://library.rice.edu/collections/WRC/finding-aids/university-archives/ua226-3